# Thomas Davisas

♦ https://lordajax.com

• thomasdavis

• ajaxdavis

I'm a full stack web developer who can build apps from the ground up. I've worked mostly at startups so I am used to wearing many hats. I am a very product focused developer who prioritizes user feedback first and foremost. I'm generally very flexible when investigating new roles.

# Experience

# **Product Engineer**

May 2020 — Present

Misc Companies

Over the past several years, I've worked at various roles and companies. Mostly early stage startups, doing full stack product development.

- React / Next
- Node / Laravel
- LLM's
- Diagrams / Canvas

## Senior Javascript Developer

 $May\ 2020\ -\ May\ 2021$ 

Tokenized 2

Tokenized is a Bitcoin wallet for issuing, managing and trading digital tokens. I built out the front end which was packaged as an electron app. It was a difficult frontend to build because we store the users keys locally and used them to sign transactions and contracts.

- React
- Redux
- SCSS
- Product

## Senior Javascript Developer

March 2018 — January 2020

Blockbid

Blockbid is an Australian crypto currency exchange. I started off on the frontend but eventually became lead tech and worked on every moving piece of the exchange. I really enjoyed working with liquidity providers and connecting their platforms to help us achieve liquid markets.

- React, Apollo, Styled Components
- Node.js / Rails
- Docker / Heroku / GCP
- Used Figma for design and UX work
- Optimizing markets with tens of millions of rows using SQL.

#### Developer

January 2016 — January 2018

Listium

Built a very large and complex React / Redux application. It works on all platforms and has IOS/Android builds due to it being a PWA. (wrapped it in React Native though only implementing a WebView)

- Worked with Postgres, Redis and Dynamodb for storage.
- Hosted on a mixture of Heroku Apps and EC2 servers.
- Caching by Fastly and Cloudflare
- Hybrid app supported on all platforms

#### Developer

April 2014 — January 2016

Electronic Frontier Foundation

Hired to take EFF's campaigning to the next level by building an action centre in Ruby on Rails. The action centre is built around some large open source tools that lower the barrier to entry when contacting congress.

- Developed new tools for contacting congress
- Brainstormed campaign ideas to raise maximum awareness about issues

• Lots of social networking integration

CTO

March 2013 — January 2015

Earbits

Started off as a front end developer but took on the role of CTO in early 2013. The application frontend is built with Javascript and organized as a single page application that talks to a collection of Rails web servers which are connected to MongoDB.

- Managed a small team of developers and designers
- Built the entire frontend application with Backbone.js
- Transferred all of the infrastructure from Heroku to AWS

Founder

April 2014 — Present

JSON Resume

JSON Resume is a community driven open source initiative to create a JSON based standard for resumes. There is no reason why there can't be a common standard for writing a resume that can be extended with an ecosystem of open source tools.

- This resume is built with JSON Resume
- Over 3000 stars on Github
- Community developed themes
- Tens of thousands of users

Developer

June 2013 — January 2016

Task force. is

Worked on many politically charged campaigns against mass surveillance. Not only technically challenging work but also a lot of networking and getting my hands dirty with politics. Our biggest project was "TheDayWeFightBack"..

- Generated 37,000,000 banner views
- 100, 000 phone calls to congress
- 500, 000 emails
- 250, 000 signatures

Co-Founder

January 2013 — Present

Drone Hire

An international directory of civilian drone / UAV operators for hire. Services include aerial photography, aerial video, mapping, surveying, precision agriculture, real estate photography, remote inspections and infrared imaging. Our plan is to be the place to go when looking for UAV/Drone services. The website is built in Backbone.js and API is built with Node.js and Postgres.

• The site and blog combined have managed to receive over 200,000 visitors in 2014.

Founder

January 2011 — January 2014

Backbone Tutorials.com

I write tutorials and blog post regarding the popular Javascript framework Backbone.js. The tutorials cover a range of topics regarding front end development aimed at beginners, experts and anyone in between.

- Over two million unique visitors a year
- 25,000+ ebook downloads
- 300,000+ Youtube views

#### Front-end Developer

January 2011 — June 2012

Ephox

Ephox is a worldwide company who is heavily involved with the development of TinyMce and enterprise editors. My primary role included building front-end widgets and applications. Worked on a major product using Backbone.js as a base. Heavily involved in UI/UX design and wire-framing. Also spend a lot of time designing API specifications and documentation.

# **Projects**

JSON Resume

April 2014 — Present

JSON Resume is a community driven open source initiative to create a JSON based standard for resumes. There is no reason why there can't be a common standard for writing a resume that can be extended with an ecosystem of open source tools.

• This resume is built with JSON Resume

- Over 3000 stars on Github
- Community developed themes
- Tens of thousands of users

## Cdnjs

January 2011 — Present

Following Google's CDN for jQuery, we decided to start a CDN for the less popular Javascript frameworks. The CDN is community moderated and open source on GitHub. We secured a partnership with Cloudflare who now supports the infrastructure.

- Millions of sites use the CDN in production
- Larger market share than Yahoo's, Microsoft's and Google's javascript content distribution networks
- We serve hundreds of billions request a month
- Contains over 3000 popular Javascript libraries
- Millions of developers visit the site per year

# Education

## The University of Queensland

February 2008 — December 2009

Bachelors in Software Engineering (incomplete)

#### Awards

#### Defender of the Internet

October 2014

Fight For The Future

For my work against mass surveillance and building out civic tools for digital democracy.

# Languages

**English:** Native speaker

#### Skills

Frontend: HTML / JSX, SCSS / CSS / BEM / Styled Components, Javascript / Typescript, React / Next, Redux / Apollo

Backend: Node, Ruby, Python, Postgres, Redis, Serverless

Devops: AWS, G Cloud, Heroku, Caching

#### Interests

Gardening: Lazy Gardening Music: Guitar, Singing, Dancing **Books:** Reading, Writing, History

Open Source: All of it

## References

## Joey Flores, Co-founder and CEO of Earbits, Inc.

Thomas was hired as a lead developer and, upon the leaving of our co-founder took over as CTO of Earbits. Thomas is, hands down, one of those A Players you hear of companies dying to hire. He is incredibly smart, not just at code but about everything from classical music to Chinese language and culture. Thomas is great to work with and, as a well established contributor to open source projects and several successful ventures, commands the respect of engineers at all levels. I would suggest doing anything you can to have him on your team.

## Yotam Rosenbaum, SVP of Operations, Earbits, Inc.

I've had the great pleasure of working with Thomas for the past three years at Earbits, and on a few side projects. Two years ago our CTO left on a moment's notice, Thomas saved our company by quickly stepping up to fill this role. He has been with our company through thick and thin and made serious personal sacrifices in order to help the company during tough times. He is a phenomenal hacker and a true team player. Highly recommended!

## Ryan Kirkman, Senior Software Engineer at Nerdwallet

Thomas is an extremely talented engineer with a very broad range of skills and experience. From being a thought leader in the front-end community via backbonetutorials.com and

10/11/25, 10:33 AM Thomas Davisas - Resume

cdnjs.com, to designing and implementing the API for cdnjs.com, working with Thomas has been fantastic learning experience. Thomas is truly a full stack develop, and his work output is incredible. If there is any opportunity to work with Thomas, I take it. He is the definition of an A player.

## **Greg Davis**

On Thomas Davis... Hire this guy. Do not be fooled. Incredibly capable and fast. Plays well with others. Unbelievable at front-end work end programming but that is just the start. Visionary. Hire him before I do.